Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Collections of Artwork & Associated Material, 1850-1962; Series III; 22.74; (21 boxes)
  - BURBANK, E. A.
    - "Santa Clara Indian Pueblo. Santa Clara, N.M." Pencil drawing with gouache, 24.2 x 17.4 cm., 1938 (Box 14, Folder 272)
      Signed. Title continues: "On top of house is a wooden cage to keep eagles in"
    - "Weasel Tail. S. Cheyenne." Colored pencil[?], 21.5 x 15.2 cm., 1898 (Box 14, Folder 273)
    - [Four color prints copyrighted Brush & Pencil: Si-You-Wee-Teh-Ze-Sah, Zy-You-Wah, Si-We-Kah.] 27.8 x 20.4 cm. and smaller (Box 14, Folder 274)
      With duplicates of Si-You-Wee-Teh-Ze-Sah and Si-We-Ka, signed by Burbank
    - [Nine color prints: Chief Geronimo, Chief Black-Coyote, Red-Woman, Chief Chief-Killer, Straight-Crazy, Weasel Tail.] 28.1 x 20.4 cm. and smaller (Box 14, Folder 275)
      Series A, nos. 2, 3, 4, 10, 11, 13. With duplicates of nos. 2, 4, 13, signed by Burbank
    - [Seven color prints by the Chicago Colortype Co.: Chief Joseph, Quin-Cha-Ke-Cha, Gi-Aum-E Hon-O-Me-Tah, Wick-Ah-Te-Wah.] 27.9 x 19.6 cm. and smaller (Box 14, Folder 276)
      With duplicates of Gi-Aum-E Hon-O-Me-Tah, and Wick-Ah-Te-Wah, signed by Burbank
    - Dummy for front cover and spine for Burbank Among the Indians published in 1944, 23.5 x 21 cm. (Box 14, Folder 277)
  - HALL, BOB
    - Original Artwork
      - "Crow Indian." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, visible image 24 x 33.2 cm. (Box 14, Folder 278)
      - "F.E.R.A. Tannery Project. Butte, Montana." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 71 x 56 cm.
        Stored in: Oversize box 55, folder 1085
      - [Gamblers.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 27 x 46 cm. (Box 14, Folder 279)
      - [Horse.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 30.6 x 20.6 cm., 1962 (Box 14, Folder 280)
      - [Horse grazing by a fence.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 16.1 x 21.5 cm. (Box 14, Folder 281)
        Signed and inscribed to the Stenzels
      - [Horse grazing by log cabin.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 29.4 x 37 cm. (Box 14, Folder 282)
        Signed. Pencil and pen-and-ink drawings of horses grazing on verso
      - [Horse standing by cabin.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 25.1 x 20.3 cm. (Box 14, Folder 283)
      - [Log cabin.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 12.3 x 14.5 cm. (Box 14, Folder 284)
      - [Log cabin with mountain in background.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 21.8 x 28.4 cm., 1962 (Box 14, Folder 285)
        Inscribed to the Stenzels with pencil note on verso
      - [Man sketching with horse standing nearby.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 25.2 x 20.3 cm. (Box 14, Folder 286)
      - [Moose.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 29 x 37 cm. (Box 14, Folder 287)
      - [Native American hunting buffalo.] Two pen-and-ink drawings, 36.9 x 29.2 cm. and smaller (Box 14, Folder 288)
        Two drawings, one signed
      - [Native American on horseback.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 33.4 x 38.8 cm. (Box 14, Folder 289)
      - [Native American on horseback with papoose and travois.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 28 x 37.1 cm. (Box 14, Folder 290)
      - [Native American warrior on horseback.] Three pen-and-ink and watercolor drawings, 38.8 x 28.4 cm. and smaller (Box 14, Folder 291)
        Three drawings, one signed
      - [Native American warrior on horseback in front of tepee.] Two pen-and-ink and watercolor drawings, 55.8 x 38.2 cm. and smaller, 1962, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 292)
        Two signed drawings
      - [Native American watching wagon train from behind rock.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 46.7 x 58.3 cm., 1953 (Box 14, Folder 293)
      - [Native Americans painting a horse.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 36.2 x 53.8 cm., 1953 (Box 14, Folder 294)
      - "So Near Yet So Far." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 25.6 x 20.3 cm. (Box 14, Folder 295)
      - [Two men on horseback.] Two pen-and-ink and watercolor, 29.2 x 36.7 cm. and smaller (Box 14, Folder 296)
        Two drawings, one of them inscribed at bottom: "Greetings Doc from Bob Hall"
      - [Two saddled horses in front of building.] Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 24.3 x 22.8 cm. (Box 14, Folder 297)
        Inscribed at bottom: "Greetings from the Halls To Mr. and Mrs. Doc Stenzel"
      - "Wm. Standing." Pen-and-ink drawing, 43.1 x 58.6 cm. (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - Prints
      - "Bob Hall's Historic Montana Stationery." Stationery with images by Hall, 19.5 x 29 cm., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 299)
      - [Horses tied up in front of small store.] Print, 15 x 17.7 cm., n.d. (Box 14, Folder 300)
      - "Old Time Cow Spread." Pen-and-ink drawing, 58.5 x 74 cm.
      - Postcards (34 postcards of 23 images), n.d.
      - [Two horses tied up in front of a blacksmith's.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 56 x 76 cm., 1954
        Pencil and pen-and-ink drawing of one Native American seated drawing a buffalo on a rock, with another Native American nearby on horseback next to two horses
  - HEYWOOD, HERBERT
    - "Astoria Column." Print, 17.1 x 13.4 cm. (Box 15, Folder 301)
    - "The Battleship Oregon." Print, 13.6 x 17 cm. and smaller (Box 15, Folder 302)
      Two prints, one signed
    - "The Circuit Rider." Print, 13.8 x 17.4 cm., and smaller (Box 15, Folder 303)
    - "The Columbia River." Print, 17.5 x 13.3 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - "Crown Point and Vista House." Print, 17.2 x 13.3 cm. (Box 15, Folder 305)
    - "The Highclimber." Print, 17.2 x 13.4 cm. and smaller (Box 15, Folder 306)
      Two prints
    - "Mount Baker." Print, 13.3 x 17.4 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - "Mt. Hood." Print, 16.6 x 12.6 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 308)
    - "Multnomah Falls." Print, 17.4 x 13.3 cm. (Box 15, Folder 309)
    - "Sacajawea." Print, 17.1 x 12.5 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 310)
    - "St. John's Bridge." Print, 17.5 x 13.3 cm. and smaller (Box 15, Folder 311)
    - "Skidmore Fountain." Print, 13.5 x 17.2 cm. (Box 15, Folder 312)
    - "Tillamook Light." Print, 13.2 x 16.6 cm. (Box 15, Folder 313)
  - KEHOE, JOSEPH W. (JOSEPH WILLIAM)
    - [Building at foot of mountains.] Watercolor, 18.5 x 26.2 cm., 1944 (Box 15, Folder 314)
    - [Buildings in snow.] Watercolor, 26.2 x 36 cm., 1945 May (Box 15, Folder 315)
    - [Canoe on stand.] Watercolor, 21.8 x 28.4 cm. (Box 15, Folder 316)
    - [City at foot of mountains.] Watercolor, 25 x 37.5 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 317)
      Watercolor of mountain range on verso
    - [Dogsled heading towards cabins.] Watercolor, 25 x 35 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 318)
    - [Dogsled in foreground, cabins in background.] Watercolor, 23.5 x 34 cm. (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - [Elevated structure for fish drying(?) next to tepee.] Watercolor, 22.3 x 28.9 cm. (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - "Fortune Ledge." Watercolor, 22.0 x 32.4 cm., 1946 (Box 15, Folder 321)
    - [Lighthouse.] Watercolor, visible image 26 x 37 cm., n.d.
      Possibly by Kehoe
    - [Man fishing near covered bridge, mountains in background.] Watercolor, visible image 33 x 43.5 cm.
      Stored in: Oversize box 55, folder 1089
    - [Man fishing, two figures cleaning fish, at Celilo Falls?] Watercolor, 35.4 x 45 cm., 1955
      Verso has a watercolor of a town with mountains in the background
    - [Pier with boats, one named Carol Ann.] Watercolor, 26.5 x 36.5 cm., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 322)
    - [Ship surrounded by ice.] Watercolor, 30.8 x 22.2 cm. (Box 15, Folder 323)
    - [Shoreline buildings, one with an American flag.] Watercolor, 25 x 37.6 cm. (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - [Shoreline with beached canoes and low buildings.] Watercolor, 22.2 x 33 cm. (Box 15, Folder 325)
    - [Street scene.] Watercolor, 22.7 x 30.4 cm. (Box 15, Folder 326)
    - [Two small buildings.] Watercolor, 22 x 29.7 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 327)
    - [View of buildings - Candle Hotel sign on one of them.] Watercolor, 22.5 x 30.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 328)
    - [Waterfront scene with mountains in background.] Watercolor, 24.9 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 329)
    - [Winter Scene.] Watercolor, visible image 25.5 x 35.7 cm., n.d.
  - KLEIBER, HANS
    - See also Will James in box 38, folders 733-734
    - Original Artwork
      - "Across the Prairies." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.8 x 25.3 cm. on sheet 27.9 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 330)
      - "Along the Bighorns, Wyoming. Afternoon." Oil painting, 31.5 x 41.3 cm. (Box 16, Folder 331)
      - "Band of Sheep on Powder River." Pen-and-ink drawing, 20.3 x 30.6 cm. on sheet 28.2 x 35.8 cm. (Box 16, Folder 332)
      - "A Burial on the Prairie." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.5 x 25.6 cm. on sheet 29.9 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 333)
      - "Cooke City, Montana." Pen-and-ink drawing, 14.2 x 22.9 cm. on sheet 27.8 x 35.6 cm. (Box 16, Folder 334)
        Signed. Verso has pen-and-ink drawing, "In the Bighorns" with "Christmas Greetings from the Bighorn Country" written next to the drawing. 16.5 x 11.5 cm.
      - "Crossing the Platte." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.8 x 28 cm. on sheet 25.6 x 35.6 cm. (Box 16, Folder 335)
        Signed. Sketch of same image on verso in pencil
      - "Down from the Hills." Pen-and-ink drawing, 30.2 x 41 cm. (Box 16, Folder 336)
      - "Early Morning on Powder River, Wyoming." Oil painting, 21.4 x 30.1 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 337)
      - "Evening on the Overland Trail." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.7 x 25.5 cm. on sheet 28.8 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 338)
      - "A Flock of Canvas backs in Flight." Watercolor, 41 x 32.5 cm., n.d.
      - "Ft. Laramie - 1846." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.7 x 26.8 cm. on sheet 28 x 35.7 cm. (Box 16, Folder 339)
      - "Juncos." Watercolor, 33.7 x 27.2 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 340)
      - "Knife River Post Office." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.9 x 28.1 cm. on sheet 22.8 x 28.2 cm. (Box 16, Folder 341)
      - "Leaving the Frontier." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.7 x 25.5 cm. on sheet 28 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 342)
      - "A Log Boom -- Morning." Watercolor, 29.9 x 40.8 cm., n.d.
      - "The Long Trail." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.9 x 35.5 on sheet 28.1 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 343)
      - "Low Camp in Bighorn." Pen-and-ink drawing, 20.3 x 27.9 cm. on sheet 22.9 x 27.9 cm. (Box 16, Folder 344)
        Related Archival Materials note
        See also: "Visitors" etching, box 17, folder 367
      - "Meneaska." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.8 x 25.5 cm. on sheet 28 x 25.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 345)
        Signed. Manuscript note on verso: "Meneaska means 'White Man.'"
      - "Mountain Chickadees." Watercolor, 27.7 x 37.3 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 346)
      - "On the Clearwater River, Idaho." Watercolor, 27 x 37.2 cm., n.d.
      - "Ranchester - Wyoming." Watercolor, 27 x 37.2 cm., n.d.
      - "Returning from an Elk Hunt." Pen-and-ink drawing, 25.3 x 35.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 347)
      - "Summer Low Camp in Big Horn." Pen-and-ink drawing, 30.2 x 40.8 cm. (Box 16, Folder 348)
        See also: "At the Hitchrack" etching, folder 350
      - "Waiting at the Gate." Pen-and-ink drawing, 28.7 x 39.2 cm. (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - Etchings
      - "At the Hitchrack." Colored, plate mark 25 x 35.1 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 350)
        See also: "Summer Low Camp in Big Horn" drawing, folder 348
      - "At the Hitchrack." Colored, plate mark 24.9 x 35.1 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 351)
      - "At the Silver Dollar." Colored, plate mark 21.4 x 30.2 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 352)
      - "A Burial on the Prairie." Colored, plate mark 17.3 x 25 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 353)
      - "Canadian Geese." Colored, plate mark 22.6 x 32.7 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 354)
      - "Cooke City." Plate mark 13.6 x 22.5 cm. (Box 16, Folder 355)
        Inscribed at bottom: "With fondest remembrances to Kathy and Dr. Franz Stenzel from Hans Kleiber, July 10, 1961"
      - "Crossing the Platte." Colored, plate mark 17.5 x 27.5 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 356)
      - "Down From the Hills." Colored, plate mark 21.1 x 30 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 357)
      - "Fort Laramie 1846." Colored, plate mark 17.6 x 26.5 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 358)
      - "Honkers Settling." Colored, plate mark 25 x 35 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 359)
      - "Knife River Post Office." Colored, plate mark 17.4 x 27.5 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 360)
      - "Leaving the Frontier." Colored, plate mark 17.4 x 25 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 361)
      - "Mallards Coming In." Colored, plate mark 25 x 35.2 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 362)
      - "My Home Town." Plate mark 10 x 16.2 cm. (Box 16, Folder 363)
        Inscribed at bottom: "A little going-away souvenir for a most pleasant visit July 10, 1961 from the House of Stenzel"
      - "Pheasants III." Colored, plate mark 25.1 x 20 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 364)
      - "Pintails Coming In." Plate mark 15 x 18.8 cm., n.d. (Box 16, Folder 365)
      - "Pinto Mare and Colt." Colored, plate mark 21.2 x 30.2 cm. (Box 17, Folder 366)
      - "Visitors." Colored, plate mark 19.9 x 27.7 cm., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 367)
        See also: "Low Camp in Bighorn" drawing, box 16, folder 348
      - "Waiting at the Gate." Colored, plate mark 21.4 x 30 cm., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 368)
        See also: "Visitors" drawing, box 17, folder 367
      - "The Winter Trail." Colored, plate mark 19.9 x 32.5 cm., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 369)
      - "The Winter Trail." Colored, plate mark 19.9 x 32.5 cm., 1931 (Box 17, Folder 370)
  - MARTINEZ, PETE
    - [Corral with horseman and three cows.] Pen-and-ink drawing, visible image 18 x 23.5 cm. (Box 17, Folder 371)
    - [Cowboy on horse lassoing calf.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 27.4 x 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 372)
    - [Cowboy on horse with lasso.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 13.2 x 16 cm., 1947 (Box 17, Folder 373)
    - "The Day Off." Watercolor, 20 x 25.2 cm., on mat 30.5 x 35.5 cm. (Box 17, Folder 374)
    - "Driving the Beef from the YP Ranch to the Rail-road." Print, 11.9 x 15.2 cm. on sheet 20.3 x 25.3 cm., 1934 (Box 17, Folder 375)
    - "Earning His Pay." Etching, plate mark 20 x 24.5 cm., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 376)
    - "Hi-in-the-Saddle." Colored etching, plate mark 23.7 x 33.7 cm., 1960 (Box 17, Folder 377)
    - "A Longhorn Caught Short." Colored etching, plate mark 16.8 x 19.9 cm., 1962 (Box 17, Folder 378)
    - "The Old Snake River in Idaho." Pencil drawing, 16.5 x 25.7 cm., 1923 (Box 17, Folder 379)
    - "On Round-up." Etching, plate mark 12.4 x 17.6 cm. (Box 17, Folder 380)
    - "The Only Man that Could Ride Him." Colored etching, plate mark 22 x 17.6 cm. (Box 17, Folder 381)
    - "Owhyee Indian Agency Sketched one Sunday." Pencil drawing, 17 x 23.5 cm. on sheet 22.5 x 30 cm., 1923 May (Box 17, Folder 382)
    - "Pratice [sic] Day." Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.5 x 24.8 cm. (Box 17, Folder 383)
  - MCENTEE, JERVIS
    - Correspondence
      - Incoming
        - The American Cyclopaedia, 1874 Oct 27 (Box 18, Folder 384)
        - Boughton, George Henry, 1870, 1879 (Box 18, Folder 385)
        - Gifford, Sanford Robinson, 1860-80 (Box 18, Folder 386)
        - Johnson, Eastman, 1863-87, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 387-389)
        - McEntee, Jno., 1887 Aug 12 (Box 18, Folder 390)
        - National Academy of Design, 1861 May 9 (Box 18, Folder 391)
        - Sawyer, C. M., 1850, 1879 (Box 18, Folder 392)
        - Sawyer, Oscar, 1879 Mar 4 (Box 18, Folder 393)
        - Smith, William Prescott, 1866 Mar (Box 18, Folder 394)
        - Stoddard, R. H., 1870 Sep 7 (Box 18, Folder 395)
        - Taylor, Marie, 1877 Feb 4 (Box 18, Folder 396)
        - Thompson, Launt, 1865, 1869 (Box 18, Folder 397)
        - Weir, John Ferguson, 1866-88 (Box 18, Folder 398)
        - Whittredge, Worthington, 1857-90 (Box 18, Folder 399-402)
        - Yale School of Fine Arts, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 403)
        - Youmans[?], K. L., 1869 Aug 8 (Box 18, Folder 404)
        - Unidentified, 1875 Oct 13 (Box 18, Folder 405)
      - Outgoing
        - Vaux, Calvert, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 406)
        - Vaux, Mrs. Calvert, 1868 Aug 15 (Box 18, Folder 407)
      - Third Party Correspondence
        - Farnham, C. H. to "Vance", 1889 Aug 21 (Box 18, Folder 408)
        - "Maurice" to "Father", 1882 Jul 9 (Box 18, Folder 409)
    - Printed Material
      - Jervis McEntee's calling card, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 410)
      - Clippings, 1895, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 411)
  - MCILWRAITH, WILLIAM FORSYTH
    - Drawings
      - "Blitz Weinhard." Pastel, 19 x 15 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 412)
        Title from mat
      - "Boathouse." Pastel, 31.4 x 22.8 cm., 1930 (Box 19, Folder 413)
        Signed. Title from mat
      - "Building Morning Star." Pastel, 22.7 x 31.4 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 414)
      - "Building St. Johns Bridge." Pastel, 38 x 24.1 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 415)
      - "Closeup Burnside Bridge Tower with Boats." Pen-and-ink over pencil, 39.2 x 25.3 cm. (irregular) (Box 19, Folder 416)
      - "The Forestry Building." Pen-and-ink, watercolor and gouache, 25.5 x 35.5 cm.
        Possibly McIlwraith. Title from mat
      - "Harbor Scene III." Pastel, 23.7 x 31.7 cm. (Box 19, Folder 417)
      - "Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo." Pencil, 26.9 x 21.7 cm. (Box 19, Folder 418)
      - "Loading Ship at Steel Bridge." Pastel, 25.7 x 32.7 cm. (irregular), 1934 Feb 1 (Box 19, Folder 419)
      - "Mill Terminal Docks." Pencil, 22.8 x 30.1 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 420)
      - "Pioneer P.O." Charcoal and gouache, 24.1 x 29 cm. on sheet 32 x 34.4 cm.
        Possibly by McIlwraith. Title from mat
      - "Sailing ship at Pier 5." Pastel, 28.7 x 22 cm. on sheet 31.2 x 23.2 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 421)
      - "Small Boats Chained to Pier." Pencil, 28 x 22.5 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 422)
      - "Steamboat Farm." Pen-and-ink over pencil, 18 x 27.6 cm. (Box 19, Folder 423)
      - [Steamboat Farm.] Pencil, 23 x 28.5 cm. on sheet 26.5 x 30.2 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 424)
      - "Steel bridge." Pastel, 31.4 x 22.4 cm., n.d.
      - "Three Ships in Harbor." Pastel, 24 x 34.9 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 425)
      - "Timberline Lodge - Front view." Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 26 x 36.6 cm. on sheet 38.2 x 47.8 cm.
    - Watercolors
      - "Boat docked at feed store." 17.6 x 25.2 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 426)
      - "Grain elevator on Willamette." 25.1 x 17.6 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 427)
      - "Harbor Scene I." 17.7 x 25.2 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 428)
      - "Harbor Scene II." 19 x 28 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 429)
      - [Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo.] 50 x 37.6 cm.
      - [Logging mill?] 18 x 25.5 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 430)
      - "Moving logs by pulley at mill." 18.9 x 28 cm., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 431)
      - "Riverboat & tug pulled up to land." 17.9 x 25.5 cm. (Box 20, Folder 432)
      - "Sawdust at dock to be loaded." 17.9 x 25.5 cm., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 433)
      - "Steamboat Farm in W.C." 24.5 x 30.6 cm. (Box 20, Folder 434)
      - "Steel Bridge #1." 35.8 x 28.2 cm., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 435)
      - "Two docked sternwheelers." 17.6 x 25.1 cm. (Box 20, Folder 436)
    - Prints
      - "Along Shore." Etching, plate mark 21.4 x 15.2 cm., 1925 (Box 20, Folder 437)
      - "Battleship Oregon." Offset lithograph, 23 x 26.2 cm. on sheet 25.4 x 30.4 cm., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 438)
      - "Battleship Oregon." Offset lithograph, 22.9 x 26.3 cm. on sheet 28.5 x 33.6 cm. (Box 20, Folder 439)
      - "Boats tied up at Pier. Seattle & Portland Boats named." Etching, plate mark 19 x 24 cm. (Box 20, Folder 440)
      - "Building the Morning Star." Etching, plate mark 24 x 35.9 cm. on sheet 32.1 x 44.6 cm., n.d.
      - "Building the Star of Oregon - 1841." Offset lithograph, 34.9 x 47.8 cm., n.d.
        Printed by James, Kerns & Abbott Company
      - "Burnside Bridge." Etching, plate mark 35.9 x 20.9 cm. on sheet 41.5 x 27.6 cm.
      - "Burnside Bridge Tower." Etching, plate mark 35.7 x 20.8 cm. on sheet 40.1 x 26.9 cm., 1932
        Stored in: Oversize box 58, folder 1123
      - "Chaneling Logs from shoot to River with Peavey." Etching, plate mark 23.5 x 16 cm., n.d. (Box 20, Folder 441)
      - "Forestry Building. Portland, Oregon." Offset lithograph, 20.7 x 31.8 cm. on sheet 26.4 x 38.5 cm. (Box 20, Folder 442)
      - "Forestry Building. Portland, Oregon." Offset lithograph, 20.7 x 31.8 cm. on sheet 24.7 x 33 cm. (Box 20, Folder 443)
      - "Forestry Building. Portland, Oregon." Offset lithograph, 20.7 x 31.8 cm. on sheet 27.5 x 38.5 cm. (Box 20, Folder 444)
      - "Home of Forgotten Men." Etching, plate mark 22 x 28 cm., 1931 (Box 20, Folder 445)
      - [Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo.] Etching, plate mark 21.2 x 19.5 cm. (Box 20, Folder 446)
      - [Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo.] Etching, plate mark 18.6 x 17.3 cm. (Box 20, Folder 447)
      - [Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo, detail.] Etching, plate mark 29 x 21 cm. (Box 20, Folder 448)
      - "Loading Logs." Etching, plate mark 26.4 x 17.5 cm. (Box 20, Folder 449)
      - [Logging operation.] Etching, plate mark 14.5 x 20.6 cm., 1924 (Box 21, Folder 450)
      - "McLoughlin Home, Oregon City, Ore." Offset lithography, 21.2 x 25.8 cm. on sheet 28.2 x 33.5 cm., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 451)
      - "Motor Buses." Etching, plate mark 15.8 x 30 cm., 1934 (Box 21, Folder 452)
      - "The Norway Maru in Portland Harbor." Lithograph, 19 x 28 cm. on sheet 23.5 x 33 cm., 1932 (Box 21, Folder 453)
      - "Old warehouses." Etching, plate mark 19.5 x 22.2 cm., 1925 (Box 21, Folder 454)
        Signed. "Edition limited to 50 copies of which this is No. 3"
      - "Old Wharf - Portland." Etching, plate mark 20.7 x 15.6 cm., 1930 (Box 21, Folder 455)
        Signed. "Edition limited to 25 copies"
      - "Oregon State Capitol 1873-1935." Lithograph, 24 x 25 cm. on sheet 30 x 33.5 cm., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 456)
      - "Ruins of the State House." Etching, plate mark 27.3 x 18.5 cm. on sheet 36 x 25.4 cm., 1936
      - "Skidmore Fountain. Erected 1888." Offset lithograph, 25.4 x 21.7 cm. on sheet 37.5 x 31.5 cm., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 457)
        At bottom: "James, Kerns & Abbott Company, Portland's Master Printers"
      - "Steamboat Landing." Etching, plate mark 18.1 x 20.5 cm., 1933 (Box 21, Folder 458)
      - [Steamship T. J. Potter.] Lithograph, 21.6 x 25.7 cm. on sheet 28.3 x 31.2 cm. (Box 21, Folder 459)
      - [Steamship T. J. Potter.] Lithograph, 21.6 x 25.7 cm. on sheet 28 x 33.5 cm., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 460)
      - [Steamship T. J. Potter.] Lithograph, 21.5 x 25.6 cm. on sheet 29.2 x 33.5 cm. (Box 21, Folder 461)
      - "Steel Bridge." Etching, plate mark 12.2 x 11 cm., 1926 (Box 21, Folder 462)
        Signed. "Edition limited to 50 copies of which this is No 2"
      - "Timberline Lodge, Mt. Hood, Oregon." Lithograph of an etching, visible image 25 x 32 cm., n.d.
        Accompanied by an advertisement for the lodge
      - "Timberline Lodge with Skiers - View from left end." Etching, plate mark 23.5 x 36 cm. on sheet 33 x 45.8 cm.
      - "Trolling boat." Etching, plate mark 16.5 x 15.5 cm. (Box 21, Folder 463)
      - "Trouble Shooter." Etching, plate mark 23 x 15 cm., 1934 (Box 21, Folder 464)
      - "Under the Bridge." Etching, plate mark 19 x 12.8 cm. (Box 21, Folder 465)
      - "Wild Bill Hickock." Etching, plate mark 18.2 x 11.1 cm., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 466)
        Same image as "Doc Holliday etching plate box 22, folder 472
      - [Wild Bill Hickock.] One pen-and-ink sketch, one etching, 18.6 x 11.4 cm. and smaller (Box 21, Folder 467)
    - Etching Plates
      - The titles for the zinc and copper etching plates were obtained from acidic paper wrappers which were photocopied and discarded.
      - "Boat Building - Fulton." Zinc, 20.3 x 15.1 cm., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 468)
      - "Burnside Bridge." Zinc, 36.2 x 20.8 cm. (Box 22, Folder 469)
      - "Columns of the Past?" Copper, 27.5 x 18.6 cm., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 470)
      - "The Course of Empire." Zinc, 14.3 x 23.1 cm., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 471)
      - "Doc Holliday Etching." Zinc, 18.4 x 11.1 cm., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 472)
      - [Home of Forgotten Men.] Zinc, 22.1 x 28.4 cm., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 473)
      - "Indians Salmon Fishing at Celilo." Zinc, 21.8 x 19.8 cm. (Box 23, Folder 474)